#### **ABOUT**

A Full Stack Application Developer with experience working as a UI, UX, and QA engineer, systems administrator. Current career goals and objectives include designing and implementing enterprise-scale systems, minimizing costs and maximizing performance of software solutions, improving operational efficiency of organizations, learning new technologies to overcome business challenges, empowering and leading effective teams of engineers. Interested in analytics, finance, and investing.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Babson College**

Application Developer

Babson Park, MA Apr 2014 – present

- Design, develop, and maintain complex dynamic cross-browser web applications using ACF/Fusebox, Java, PHP/Drupal, C#/.NET, JS/CSS along with their popular frameworks/libraries in enterprise level production systems while handling an ever-increasing number of users and requests of enhancement and new functionalities;
- Create enterprise-scale integration solutions for a variety of systems using SOAP and RESTful web services, APIs, ETL tools, MS SQL Server;
- Work with, use, and help configure Salesforce.com (Sales/HEDA Cloud), Informatica (ICS, DI, APIs), Workday (HCM, Financials), JIRA (on prem), SharePoint, Neoload, and other technologies.

## Recent projects:

- Designing and implementing a SFDC-based alumni engagement platform (bab.sn/connector) that serves a community of over 40,000 Babson alumni;
- Redesigning of the online giving site (<u>bab.sn/givenow</u>) into a single-page web app, resulting in an improved UX which increased number of donations - one of the primary sources of income for the college;

# **Babson College**

Software Developer Co-op / Application Developer Intern

Babson Park, MA May 2012 – Apr 2014

- Created and maintained dynamic web applications for the Babson Portal a platform of over 150 custom written tools with 2,000,000+ lines of code; researched, proposed, and integrated new software solutions;
- Wrote custom two-way web services and data feeds to integrate internal data stores and systems with a variety of third party applications and tools;
- Developed custom system workflows (XML), services, and events (JellyScript) in JIRA, performed system administration of the Atlassian stack (JIRA, Confluence) including data back-up, indexing, and restoring, system troubleshooting, patching, etc.

## Projects included:

- Developing a single page web app that streamlined the annual faculty reporting of student opinion surveys, significantly reducing time and paper required to create the reports;
- Automating the semiannual e-mail send-out of personalized print statistics as part of a
  print awareness campaign, increasing efficient printing practices and awareness of
  sustainability initiatives, resulting in several thousand dollars of reduced costs.

/

Babson Park, MA

Boston, MA

Tyumen, Russia

Sep 2008 - May 2011

May 2016 - Aug 2018

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Advanced knowledge of ACF, t-SQL, JS, CSS, XML/HTML, ETL tools (Informatica, SSIS), SOAP and RESTful web services, JIRA, Confluence.

Intermediate knowledge of C/C#, .NET, Java, PHP, Drupal, Force.com platform, SOQL/APEX/Visualforce, Workbench, git, Workday, Cvent, VSS.

Familiarity with Assembly (MASM), Python, Perl, Objective C/Swift, most flavors of shell scripting, SharePoint, Selenium, CrazyEgg, Mendix, Neoload, Laserfiche, webRTC, webVR, MEAN stack.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Babson College**

F. W. Olin Graduate School of Business Master of Business Administration (MBA)

**Business Analytics concentration** 

# **Wentworth Institute of Technology**

College of Engineering and Technology Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sep 2011 – Apr 2014 GPA: 3.82

- Dean's List (2011-2014), graduated with honors: magna cum laude
- Tau Alpha Pi Honor Society, Applied Math minor, 2014 Annual Awards Recipient
- Wentworth Community Scholarship and Wentworth Merit Scholarship Recipient

#### University of Tyumen (transferred out)

Institute of Mathematics and Computer Science

BS/MS in Mathematical Software and Information Systems Administration

- Full Tuition Scholarship
- 2008 Outstanding Incoming Class Award Recipient

#### CONFERENCES, WORKSHOPS, SEMINARS, AND HACKATHONS

- Babson Finance Conference, Mar 2018 (Boston, MA)
- TERMINALFOUR Advanced Web Developer, 3-day onsite training, Jan 2018 (Wellesley, MA)
- Reality Virtually Hack @ MIT, Oct 2017 (Cambridge, MA) Project: WebVR Checkout
- Programmatic Development Using Apex and Visualforce (DEV450), Sep 2017 (Boston, MA)
- Hacking for Good @ HBS, Jun 2017 (Boston, MA)
- InformaticaWorld, May 2017 (San Francisco, CA)
- HackWITus @ WIT, Mar 2017 (Boston, MA) Project: WebArm
- AT&T WebRTC Boston Coding Workshop, May 2016 (Boston, MA)
- Future of Wearables Scramble™ @ Babson, Apr 2016 (Wellesley, MA)
- Salesforce World Tour, Apr 2016, May 2017, Apr 2018 (Boston, MA)
- Boston Code Camps (24 27), Nov 2015, 2016 & Mar 2016, 2017 (Cambridge, MA)
- Workday Higher Education Summit, Oct 2015 (Wellesley, MA)
- Dyn's Hackademy, May 2015 (Manchester, NH) Project: Conversion Wars Web App
- NeoLoad 3-day training, Feb 2015 (Waltham, MA)
- Mendix 3-day onsite training, Aug 2014; Laserfiche 4-day training, Sep 2014 (Wellesley, MA)
- Dyn's Hackademy, May 2014 (Manchester, NH) Project: DWC Boy Scouts iOS App

VADIM MANOKHIN

manokhinv.github.io

/

manokhin.vadim@gmail.com

## **VOLUNTEER SERVICE AND ACTIVITIES**

Babson Kids on Campus Day

Babson Park, MA

Babson Garden Session Volunteer 2016 – 2018

Babson Undergraduate Commencement Babson Park, MA

Commencement Host 2016 – 2018

Babson Entrepreneurial Thought & Action (ET&A) Award Babson Park, MA

Selection Committee Member October 2016

Wentworth Admissions Office Boston, MA

Admissions Blogger Jan 2014 – Apr 2014

Wentworth Career Services Boston, MA

Web Application Developer May 2013 – Apr 2014

Wentworth International Student Services Boston, MA

International Student Ambassador Aug 2012 – Apr 2014

Wentworth President's Host Society

Boston, MA

President's Host Feb 2012 – Apr 2014

- Represented the Institute at various events, on and off campus

- Served as an ambassador of public relations in various supporting roles

- Promoted Wentworth's academic programs, services and student activities

## **Wentworth Community Partnership**

Boston, MA

Alternative Spring Break Volunteer

Mar 2012

- Focused on environmental work in the Biscayne and the Everglades National Parks, FL
- Worked with wounded birds at the Florida Keys Wild Bird Sanctuary, FL
- Worked with animals at Florida Monkey Forest Zoo, Key Largo, FL

#### **Wentworth Counseling Center & Disability Services Partnership**

Boston, MA

English II Note Taker for a Disabled Student

Oct 2011 - Dec 2011

#### AFFILIATIONS AND PERSONAL INTERESTS

- I've been a member of TAΠ (<u>Tau Alpha Pi</u>, Massachusetts Alpha Chapter), the professional honor society for engineering technology, since 2013.
- Occasionally, I participate in the local Boston technology meetups, hackathons, and user group activities such as BNT (Boston New Technology), <u>Boston AUG</u> (Atlassian User Group), <u>Code</u> <u>for Boston</u> Hack Nights, and others.
- I am a frequent Kiva.org investor.
- Outside of my day-to-day duties as a developer I enjoy cycling, creating and playing music, learning new things, and generally expanding my horizons.